Vatsal Chauhan

vatsal chauhan.com | LinkedIn | GitHub |

Frontend Developer

Highly skilled web developer with 2+ years of experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and efficient knowledge of React, and Tailwind CSS and MERN stack, committed to delivering exceptional results and driving success in every project.

Location: Rajkot, Gujarat, India

Email: adarsh.vc24@gmail.com | Mobile: 9426455118

Technical Skills

Languages : Vanilla JS, HTML5, CSS3, MongoDB(Crud), Express

Frameworks : Daisy UI Framework, React JS

Libraries : Material UI, Redux, React Router, Redux Toolkit, Tailwind

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Figma, Canva

Experience

React Developer Sep 2022 - Sep 2022

Remote – Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India Xpertzy

• Designed and developed dynamic and responsive websites using HTML, CSS, React.js

• Improved website performance and fixed the bugs related to Designs and created few custom components.

React Developer May 2023 - June 2023 InfiteAI Pvt.Ltd Rajkot, Gujarat, India

 Created a full fledged Website from scratch using the languages like HTML, React. is and designing frameworks such as Tailwind CSS.

• Created couple of custom Components from scratch and also used the animation library so call AOS library.

React Developer December 2023 - Present Crypto 306(Dubai) Rajkot-Remote, Gujarat, India

• Created Multiple Blockchain Websites UI from scratch using Tailwind Framework, React Js.

- Fixed Design Bugs using Tech Stack Vue.js.
- Worked with Framework and Tech Stack like: Mongo DB, Express, Vue, React, Framer Motion, Lottie **Animation Library**

Education

P.V. Modi School Rajkot, Gujarat, India **Higher Secondary Education** Jan 2018 - May 2020

Pandit Deendayal Energy University

Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India Bachelor of Technology in Computer Engineering Sep 2020 - May 2024

Projects

Todo List HTML, JavaScript, Tailwind Framework, MERN, gitCommands Source Code

- A todo list made using latest Tech Stack(MERN), and uploaded to the git using the github Commands
- Fully Responsive for small screen and large Screen devices, efficient implementation using react functional component using the v6 routings.

E-Commerce React.js, Git Source Code

• Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and React.js. Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Commands

Personal Portfolio React.js, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Git Source Code

- Complete Personal Portfolio from scrath using Html, CSS, React.js and fully responsive to all devices.
- Full fledged responsive website hosted on netlify and uploaded on GitHub pages using Github commands.

Movie Recommendation System(Group Project) HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Git, Django Source Code

 Complete Movie Recommendation System from scratch using Html, CSS, JavaScript, Django and fully responsive to all devices and worked as Frontend Developer

Hotel Recommendation System(Group Project)

HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Git, Django

Source Code

• Complete Hotel Recommendation System from scratch using **Html**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **Django** and fully **responsive** to all devices and worked as **Front end Developer**

CASSIST(Internship Company Project)

HTML, Tailwind CSS, MERN Stack

Live Demo

 Worked in the industrial environment along with the Web Development team and worked on the Frontend Development using React.js Tailwind CSS

Web Based Book Store App

HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, React, Firebase

Source Code

- Devolped Fully Responsive Complete Book Store App using React JS, Tailwind CSS, Backend using Firebase
- Json Placeholder API, using the ContextAPI or UseContext concept of React

BlockChain Based Land Registration System(Group Project)

HTML5, CSS3, JS, Django

- Worked as Frontend Developer along with one other memeber to implement the efficient UI Design using HTML5, CSS3, JS
- Secured **Second Rank** in overall Gujarat (SSIP Hackathon).

Certifications

- Certified by SimpliLearn for Completing JavaScript Course
- Winner of Hackathon named Anubhuti 2022
- KJSCE Hackathon Top 40(Participant) all over India Certificate
- SSIP Hackathon, Second Rank in overall Gujarat
- NPTEL Course, Exam Clearance Certificate